<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: School | Code Quorum]]></title>
  <link href="http://cdownard.github.io/blog/categories/school/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://cdownard.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-20T08:06:17-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://cdownard.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Christopher Downard]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Computer Science Degrees - What's Lacking]]></title>
    <link href="http://cdownard.github.io/blog/2014/03/07/computer-science-degrees-whats-lacking/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-07T09:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://cdownard.github.io/blog/2014/03/07/computer-science-degrees-whats-lacking</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been continuing to take classes despite working as a full-time developer. I
work in the .Net world, but my heart is more in Python. Still, I wanted exposure
to plenty of others and I&rsquo;m currently in my second class on C++.</p>

<p>What I have noticed in the various courses I have taken at institutions of higher
learning is that they don&rsquo;t teach anything remotely close to the real world. I
know this is a common claim and people cry out against the undergraduate program
not preparing people for the real world. I get that. But I have always dismissed
them.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Being a better, more rounded thinker is more important than job training, is it
not? Surely it is. I&rsquo;m not sure why no one slapped me. I&rsquo;ve had that discussion a
number of times with people. I should have been slapped. Now don&rsquo;t get me wrong.
I value and love my education. I have a degree in Politics from the University of
New Hampshire. I am versed in various literature and can hold discussions on a
number of topics (at one point I could almost do so in French).</p>

<p>But this is a false dichotomy. It&rsquo;s as if the premise only allows well-rounded
education or job training. That&rsquo;s ridiculous.</p>

<p>I believe what Computer Science majors need is less Assignment-based instruction
and more Project-based instruction. Random assignments that are isolated from
each other, meaning accomplishing one has no effect on accomplishing another,
don&rsquo;t provide the type of reinforcement that maximizes the mind we need molded
in academia. Completing a larger project with multiple parts is far more useful
to the student. These parts interact with one another. One of the best lessons
to learn early on is that changing code in one place can have small or large
effects on other parts of code.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s difficult to learn that in assignments that are 50-150 lines. But if you&rsquo;re
building on top of the product/project you&rsquo;re working on all semester, you will
naturally run in to those types of consequences and suddenly your student will
begin to think very differently. I value those that can think holistically about
a product rather than the frustratingly common linear thinker that says to the
team &ldquo;Well, I&rsquo;ll just change this and then it&rsquo;ll be fixed.&rdquo; I love it when I
hear someone say &ldquo;Well, if we change that there could be implications to these
other parts.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Admittedly, I think there&rsquo;s a lot of cruft in undergraduate coursework these
days. Taking art history doesn&rsquo;t make you a better thinker per se. You don&rsquo;t
experience art in an art history class. You learn what you need to say about a
particular painting/sculpture/etc. in order to demonstrate knowledge about the
piece. We cannot say that a mathematics major is more well-rounded for taking
such a course. Well-rounded according to whom? And how pompous to believe that
one semester of being told what to think about paintings and what is meant to be
conveyed by them makes an individual more well-rounded.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s value in education for the sake of education. I don&rsquo;t argue against that
and in fact, as a serial student, I&rsquo;m quite fond of education for its own sake.
However, the prototypical pedagogy associated with the usual assortment of
subjects and course material falls short when it comes to Computer Science.
Programming is a craft. <a href="http://norvig.com/21-days.html">It takes years to
master</a>. There are many other disciplines where
this is similar, so why not change the teaching style?</p>

<p>Students experience a couple of introductory courses and then are expected to
understand high level concepts. In my opinion, going through academia has the
primary purpose of learning how to think which implicitly means application.
Anyone who argues against that should be beaten with a stick. Socrates explored
the meta, but he focused his knowledge on teaching and applying - even if the
application was theoretical (see The Republic). If our goal is to teach people
how to think, let&rsquo;s make use of the discipline. Sorting arrays is great. It&rsquo;s
very helpful to understand a binary versus bubble sort and why one is faster or
better in certain scenarios.</p>

<p>But we&rsquo;re a community of people that build things. We command the electron to do
our bidding. We engage in digital alchemy. We are the citizens of an industry
governed by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moore%27s_law">Moore&rsquo;s law</a> and yet we
tacitly accept that there&rsquo;s not a better way to gain an education in our medium?</p>

<p>I reject that.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s build better coursework by building projects with students. When a student
ends a semester with a (probably) working application that has been built in
stages with a decent feature list there is a sense of accomplishment and a
demonstrable grasp of the concepts this project instilled.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning C]]></title>
    <link href="http://cdownard.github.io/blog/2012/10/28/learning-c/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-28T10:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://cdownard.github.io/blog/2012/10/28/learning-c</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I don&rsquo;t have years of programming experience. The time that I devote to learning languages tends to be allocated to Python or something work related (.Net). However, I&rsquo;m currently enrolled in a course focused on introductory C. At times I feel as though I have stepped into a time machine.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I used to play this video game and the people who were really obsessed maxed all their stats as much as they could. There were intense calculations that could be done. People could spend hours figuring out the best way to spellcraft their armor or weapons so that every possible point or stat could be claimed. More hours would be spent &ldquo;farming&rdquo; locations for &ldquo;drops&rdquo; to create the perfect armor set. It sounds like a complete waste of time, and maybe it was, but it was certainly fun. I was one of those obsessed people that did everything they could to maximize their &ldquo;utility.&rdquo;</p>

<p>C reminds me of this mindset. I can completely see how people who are obsessed with performance or being in control of as many aspects of a program as possible would love C. You get to control almost everything so you get to optimize almost everything. You manage your memory. You fine tune everything. No doubt C is fast, but for once in my life I find myself enjoying the automatic management I get from lots of other, higher-level languages. Obtaining input in C presents a good example:</p>

<pre><code class="C">#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;

void main ()
{
    int inputChoice;
    do {
        printf("Please make a selection from the choices (1-4): ");
        scanf("%d*[\n]");
        if (inputChoice &lt; 1 || inputChoice &gt; 4) {
            printf("Error - you have entered an invalid choice.");
        }
} (while inputChoice &lt; 1 || inputChoice &gt; 4);}
</code></pre>

<p>This is how we collect input in C. We have to protect ourselves, and an easy way for a beginner like myself in C to protect against bad data is to use a do loop. Oh, that section with <code>*[\n]</code>? Yeah. That prevents the system from trying to store the newline character (<code>\n</code>). Yep. You have to handle that.</p>

<p>The thing is, I completely understand how awesome this must have been for a long time. But now it&rsquo;s just not necessary to me to spend a lot of time doing all this when I can literally do it in one line of code in another language. Take python for example:</p>

<pre><code class="python">inputChoice = input('Please make a selection')
</code></pre>

<p>I&rsquo;m cheating because there&rsquo;s no error handling. But we can add that with a couple of lines admittedly. The point isn&rsquo;t so much the length. It&rsquo;s having to handle things like the newline character. You also can&rsquo;t test data types in C.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Higher Education Is a Gateway Drug]]></title>
    <link href="http://cdownard.github.io/blog/2012/09/23/higher-education-is-a-gateway-drug/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-23T10:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://cdownard.github.io/blog/2012/09/23/higher-education-is-a-gateway-drug</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;re like me, then you&rsquo;ve been told your whole life the same thing:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Be good. Get good grades. Get into a good school. Get a good job.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s a lot of repetition for the word &ldquo;good.&rdquo; But all of those conditions are
not sufficient to produce the final result. This mantra is espoused by parents
and society (teachers, advisors, etc.) as if it&rsquo;s a logical conclusion:
IF you&rsquo;re good and get good grades and get into a good school  THEN you&rsquo;ll get a
good job.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>This is pretty faulty logic. For the P,Q logic geeks out there you can of course
pick this apart pretty quickly. But the point here is that the good job doesn&rsquo;t
necessarily come from the previous conditions. They help, sure, but there&rsquo;s an X
factor somewhere. We can call it luck, ambition, drive, personal draw (the
nature of someone being drawn to another or &ldquo;taking a liking to&rdquo; another), and
I&rsquo;m sure many others.</p>

<p>One thing is clear: getting a good education isn&rsquo;t about getting a job. It&rsquo;s
about becoming a better thinker. I&rsquo;m not sure when we decided that time spent in
a college or university was job training, but that&rsquo;s how people treat it now. I
have been guilty of treating university education as job training. It usually
presents itself in the following form:
Why do I have to take class X? I&rsquo;ll never have to use that in my future job.
Well no kidding. If your focus is to only learn what you need for use on the
job, go get a technical certificate and just work in the real world instead of
going to university. The point of higher education is not to make better
workers. That&rsquo;s job training, technical training, conferences, and the like.
Pursue those avenues for making a better or more knowledgeable worker. The
purpose of higher education is to make better thinkers. It frustrates me to no
end to hear about how an individual believes they have no need to take an
English (that is, composition/rhetoric) course because it doesn&rsquo;t apply to their
mathematics degree.</p>

<p>Yes, it does.</p>

<p>Effectively communicating applies to all degrees and careers. If you can&rsquo;t
write, you&rsquo;re at a disadvantage. If you can only perform basic math, you&rsquo;re at a
disadvantage. You also look foolish in a meeting where you&rsquo;re discussing
projections when you don&rsquo;t understand how someone arrived at a particular
conclusion based on some basic algebraic formula. I remember thinking to myself
in a class on Natural Resources why would I possibly ever need to know what the
silver lining on a cloud is called.</p>

<p>The reality is that having an education has intrinsic value. Humans have
incredible powers of perception, but if you don&rsquo;t have a broad base of
information you can&rsquo;t draw the same conclusions. The age of Google and instant
access to information has enabled us to do more but has simultaneously resulted
in lowered expectations of what we need to know. Rather than thinking about all
the new things you can learn, instead our society takes the approach of not
needing to know something because they know where to find it.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s good for the over-achieving crowd. But it&rsquo;s bad for those who are
disinterested. Those who can use that knowledge and conclude something more
quickly are at an advantage in career competition. That&rsquo;s not to say one should
attempt to learn everything and always have it at the ready. There are
exceptions such as high level theory/equations/etc. But if you have to learn a
basic concept before using the higher one, you couldn&rsquo;t plan on what higher
level concept you needed. Competition for limited resources. Not much has
changed in the world regarding that basic tenet of existence.</p>

<p>So what&rsquo;s the point? Higher education isn&rsquo;t job training. It&rsquo;s teaching folks
how to think. Becoming a better thinker has its own intrinsic value. Getting a
major in a field focuses that thinking in a particular subject area. But
thinking isn&rsquo;t job training. And that&rsquo;s lucky for those getting an education.</p>

<p>However, it&rsquo;s a gateway drug. I made an error in choosing my undergrad,
Political Science. Not because I don&rsquo;t love the subject, but ultimately my path
in life changed enough that the degree wouldn&rsquo;t be put to use in my career.
Except that I focused heavily on writing in my undergrad and I&rsquo;m an effective
communicator. I work in technology now, at a software company. And though I
completed a year of classes for an MBA, I&rsquo;m currently enrolled and seeking my
second Bachelor&rsquo;s - in Computer Science. I&rsquo;m not positive I&rsquo;ll complete the MBA,
but as I began with Political Science and intended to pursue a JD/MBA, now I
have altered my path to pursue a BS in Computer Science and potentially an MBA
as well.</p>

<p>Education is intrinsically valuable. It is also a means to an end and we
therefore often view it as onerous or irrational in some cases. But our
collective goal should be to increase knowledge and understanding, not merely
technical merits. The latter are important, but they&rsquo;re not enough. Those
committed to attaining credentials fit the post&rsquo;s title. B.A. then M.B.A. and
concurrent B.S. That&rsquo;s definitely beginning a collection&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
