<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ide | Code Quorum]]></title>
  <link href="http://cdownard.github.io/blog/categories/ide/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://cdownard.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-20T08:36:51-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://cdownard.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Christopher Downard]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Initial Impressions of Light Table IDE]]></title>
    <link href="http://cdownard.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/initial-impressions-of-light-table-ide/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-06T10:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://cdownard.github.io/blog/2013/05/06/initial-impressions-of-light-table-ide</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://lighttable.com/">Light Table</a> is a programming integrated development
environment (IDE). But it&rsquo;s a little different compared to what is currently out
there. The author, <a href="http://plus.google.com/114990036229851937142">+Chris
Granger</a>, has focused on what we
are creating rather than getting to the creation. If that concept doesn&rsquo;t quite
make sense in your head, don&rsquo;t worry. It&rsquo;s visual. Think real-time flow of your
program. If you want to watch how a value changes as it moves through your
program you can see it in real-time. Bret Victor gave a great talk on the idea
called <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PUv66718DII">Inventing on Principle</a>.
Light Table extends this concept and the roadmap for development has a lot of
nifty fun features of programmers.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I love UX/UI. Especially when it makes stuff easier/faster/better. Light Table
is basically IDE porn.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t think I can really describe it better than that, but I&rsquo;ll try to explain
some things I like and where it has some room for improvement. I have been using
it as a primary editor for VB.Net, Python (Django), and a little JavaScript for
nearly a week. VB.Net is my day job, the others are for projects at home. For
the most part I work in <a href="http://www.sublimetext.com">Sublime Text 2</a>, which is a
fantastic editor. If you haven&rsquo;t checked it out before the go grab it and start
playing. It&rsquo;s extensible, built in Python, and has tons of plugins available.
And yes, I write VB in it. It supports VB Script which is good enough. I switch
back and forth between Visual Studio and Sublime Text 2 depending on what I&rsquo;m
working on.</p>

<p>Welcome Screen
<img class="left" src="/images/light_table_01.png" title="Light Table Welcome Screen" ></p>

<p>So clearly minimalism is heavily at play here. I&rsquo;m a fan of minimalism, so this
works for me. What you see at the top are tabs. They&rsquo;re unobtrusive. You&rsquo;ll
notice I&rsquo;m in full screen mode here, or as I like to call it: Stop messaging me
on Google Talk mode. You can hit <code>ctrl + enter</code> and it pops up the command
prompt so you can be handsfree. Which I like. Granger is a fan of VIM so there
are vim bindings that can be enabled. But I like his theory that the future of
editing code can&rsquo;t always just be that the vim, emacs, etc style of only text
visualization is the answer forever.</p>

<p>Command Bar</p>

<p><img class="left" src="/images/light_table_02.png" title="Command Bar via ctrl + enter" ></p>

<p>The UI is clean and simple. After all, you don&rsquo;t need a ton of features to get
your work done. The workspace tab allows you to bring files into the &ldquo;workspace&rdquo;
which is kind of like open folder for Sublime Text 2. What&rsquo;s different is that
you can add files or folders to this workspace from all over the place. Then
those files all show up on the quick open stuff under navigation which we&rsquo;ll get
to.</p>

<p>Light Table Workspace</p>

<p><img class="left" src="/images/light_table_03.png" title="Light Table Workspace" ></p>

<p>So any of those files on the left, or if you have multiple folders can be
removed from the workspace without affecting your files on disk. Handy feature.
But also, you can just add another folder or files to the workspace. And
everything is available to open. Double-clicking any of the files on the left
will open them for editing in the current tabset on the right. Tabsets are like
groups of tabs. You can subdivide so you can have multiple tabsets each with
multiple tabs.</p>

<p>From there we can move on to the navigate tab. It basically shows you all files
in all folders. Let&rsquo;s look at a django project.</p>

<p>Light Table Navigate</p>

<p><img class="left" src="/images/light_table_04.png" title="Light Table Navigate" ></p>

<p>One of the great things about more and more programs is the support for <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Approximate_string_matching">fuzzy
search</a>. This makes
using command bars and file openers incredibly easy but it also makes search in
general better regarding programming languages. You may have 10 methods with Get
as the beginning like GetMyFoo, GetNewBars, etc. But if you want GetMyFoo, you
can just search for Foo. Fuzzy search will find it. That concept can be expanded
on drastically in practice and in different concepts (command bar for instance,
file names, settings, and your code itself) and you get some pretty awesome
results. I&rsquo;ve loved that in Sublime Text 2 and I&rsquo;m loving using it in Light
Table.</p>

<p>The default them is also pleasant for code. It&rsquo;s not terribly high contrast but I
find it&rsquo;s easy on my eyes in a dark room. And let&rsquo;s be honest. We program in the
dark a lot. But my other favorite monokai is on there and switching is a command
and a few keystrokes away so I don&rsquo;t mind switching back and forth.</p>

<p>Light Table Default Theme</p>

<p><img class="left" src="/images/light_table_04.png" title="Light Table Navigate" ></p>

<p>If you watch the videos you&rsquo;ll see some of the wonderful things Light Table can
do, but I think the best thing going for it right now is the incredibly
responsive development. I&rsquo;m not sure if +Chris Granger is working solo or if he
has assembled a team, but I watched the repo on GitHub for issue tracking and
I&rsquo;m getting a lot of mail which is Q&amp;A and feature suggestions and bug fixes. I
love that part of it. I&rsquo;m actually learning more about the editor just by
watching the &ldquo;issues&rdquo; emails come across.</p>

<p>I think that&rsquo;s all I&rsquo;ll go into for now. I&rsquo;m using it as the IDE of choice for a
Django project at the moment and it&rsquo;ll be interesting to see what ultimately I
like and dislike at the end of that. Code Mirror&rsquo;s underlying editor has a few
bugs with the syntax in VB, but I have a feeling some of the features the
community requests will be easy to address once the plugin system is live, which
is forthcoming in 0.5. I&rsquo;m already wondering if I can build out some Django tools
for the editor, even though I&rsquo;m not sure what that would look like. It supports
virtualenvs for python, although I haven&rsquo;t tried it. Django work means I&rsquo;m not
really doing eval much unless I&rsquo;m just quickly testing pieces of a function.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll post again once I have had the opportunity to really spend a lot of hours
in it. For now, I really enjoy it. I miss some of the conveniences of Sublime
Text 2, but they&rsquo;re not anything that can&rsquo;t be resolved. And for an alpha&hellip;this
product has definitely caught my attention. I look at it and all I can think is
how amazing this is going to be.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
